a machine learning engineer at Google's Advanced Solutions Lab.
我在谷歌高级解决方案实验室担任机器学习工程师。
AI and new advancements, including new vertex AI features
such as Gen AI, Studio Model Garden, Gen AI API.
如Gen AI、Studio Model Garden、Gen AI API等。
Our objective in this short session is to give you a solid footing
在这个简短的课程中，我们的目标是让您能了解Gen
AI背后的一些基本概念，打下一个坚实的基础。
on some of the underlying concepts that make all the Gen AI magic possible.
Today I'm going to talk about the attention mechanism
今天我要谈谈注意力机制，
Let's say you want to translate in English sentence
假设您想把英语句子“the cat ate the mouse”翻译成法语。
You could use an encoder decoder.
你可以使用编码器解码器。
This is a popular model that is used to translate sentences.
这是一种常用的翻译句子的模型。
The encoder decoder takes one word at a time
编码解码器每次只处理一个单词，
and translates it at each time step.
然后在每个时间步骤进行翻译。
However, sometimes the words in the source language
然而，有时源语言中的单词并不对应目标语言中的单词。
Here's an example.
这里有一个例子。
Take the sentence Black cat ate the mouse.
这个句子是“Black cat ate the mouse”。
In this example, the first English word is black.
在这个例子中，英文中的第一个词是“black”，
However, in the translation,
但在翻译成法文的时候，
the first French word is chat, which means cat in English.
第一个词是“chat”，意思是英文中的“cat”。
So how can you train a model to focus more on
那么如何训练一个模型，让它在第一步时更多地关注“cat”
这个词，而不是“black”这个词，以提高翻译的准确度呢？
the word cat instead of the word black?
Add the first time step to improve the translation.
You can add what is called the attention mechanism to the encoder decoder.
你可以在编码解码器中加入所谓的注意力机制。
Attention mechanism is a technique that allows the neural network
注意力机制是一种让神经网络能够专注于输入序列特定部分的技术，
to focus on specific parts of an input sequence.
This is done by assigning weights to different parts of the input sequence
它通过为输入序列的不同部分分配权重来实现，
with the most important parts receiving the highest weights.
最重要的部分会获得最高的权重。
This is what a traditional RNN based encoder decoder looks like.
传统的基于RNN的编码解码器看起来是这样的：
The model takes one word at a time as input
模型一次接收一个单词作为输入，
updates the hidden state and passes it on to the next time step.
更新隐藏状态，并将其传递到下一个时间步骤。
In the end,
在结束时，只有最后的隐藏状态会传递给解码器。
only the final hidden state is passed on to the decoder.
The decoder works with the final hidden state
解码器使用最后的隐藏状态进行处理，并将其翻译为目标语言。
for processing and translates it to the target language.
An attention model differs from the traditional sequence
注意力模型与传统的序列到序列模型在两个方面有所不同。
to sequence model in two ways.
First, the encoder passes a lot more data to the decoder.
首先，编码器向解码器传递更多的数据。
So instead of just passing the final hidden state number
所以，编码器不只是将最后的隐藏状态3传递给解码器，它
会将每个时间步骤的所有隐藏状态都传递给解码器。
three to the decoder, the encoder passes
all the hidden states from each time step.
beyond just the final hidden state.
The decoder uses all the hidden state information to translate the sentence.
解码器使用所有隐藏状态的信息来翻译句子。
The second change that the attention mechanism brings is adding
注意力机制带来的第二个变化是，在产生输出之
前，注意力解码器增加了一个额外的步骤。
an extra step to the attention decoder before producing its output.
Let's take a look at what these steps are
让我们看看这些步骤是怎么让解码器只关注输入中最相关的部分的。
to focus
only on the most relevant parts of the input.
The decoder does the following.
解码器执行以下操作：
First, it looks at the set of encoder states that it has received.
首先，它会观察到它收到的编码器状态集合，
Each encoder Hidden State is associated
每个编码器的隐藏状态都与输入句子中的某个词有关。
with a certain word in the input sentence.
Second, it gives each hidden state a score.
其次，它会给每个隐藏状态一个分数。
Third in multiplies each hidden state by its
然后，它会将每个隐藏状态乘以它的softmax分数，如图所示。
soft-max score as shown here.
Thus amplifying hidden states with the highest scores
这样就可以增强得分高的隐藏状态，降低得分低的隐藏状态。
and downsizing hidden states with low scores.
If we connect all of these pieces together,
如果我们把所有这些元素都连接起来，我们
就可以看到注意力网络是如何工作的。
we're going to see how the Attention Network works.
Alpha here represents the attention rate at each time step.
这里的α表示每个时间步骤的注意力率，
H represents the hidden state of the encoder RNN
H表示编码器RNN在每个时间步骤的隐藏状态，
at each time step h subscript
RNN at each time step. With the attention mechanism
每个时间步骤的隐藏状态。有了注意力机制
in the attention diagram and ate
translates as two words, a mange,
而"ate"在法语中翻译为两个词，"a mange"。
in French. We can see the attention network
我们可以看到注意力网络在两个时间步骤内都集中在"ate"这个词上。
staying focused on the word ate for two time steps.
During the attention
在注意力步骤中，我们使用编码器隐藏状态和H4
向量来计算这个时间步骤的上下文向量a4，
step we use the encoder hidden states and the H4 vector
to calculate a context vector a four for this time step.
This is the weighted sum.
这是一个加权和。
We then concatenate H4
然后，我们将H4和a4合并成一个向量。
and a 4 into one vector.
One train jointly with the model
与模型一起训练，以预测下一个词。
to predict the next work.
The output of the feedforward neural network
这个前馈神经网络的输出代表了这个时间步骤的输出词。
indicates the output word of this time step.
This process continues till the end of sentence token
这个过程会一直持续，直到解码器生成句子结束的标记。
is generated by the decoder.
This is how you can use an attention mechanism to improve
这就是你可以如何使用注意力机制来提
高传统编码解码架构性能的方式。
the performance of a traditional encoder decoder architecture.
Thank you so much for listening.
非常感谢你的聆听。